I'm not going to annihilate
4.3 million Pakistanis
그러니 내가 아는 상급자가
직접 내리는 명령이 아니라면
조국이 그들을 쫓는다
그러니 내가 아는 상급자가
직접 내리는 명령이 아니라면
without hearing from someone
whose authority I recognize.
난 4300만 명 파키스탄 인들을
쓸어버리지 않을 걸세
Our own people
tried to sink us?
아군이 우릴
격침시키려 했다고?
We have commandeered
대담한 계획
우리는 세인트마리나 섬에 위치한
NATO의 조기경보소를 징발했다
the NATO early warning station
on the island of Sainte Marina.
I am declaring
a 200-mile no-man's-land
이 섬 주변 반경 200마일을
비무장지대로 선포한다
around this island.
시험해보라
우리 모두 불타오를 테니...
Test us, and we will all burn.
You've been warned.
경고했다
_
지난 이야기
The intel is all wrong.
정보가 틀렸습니다!
어떻게 하죠?
What did we do?
We killed the wrong people.
엉뚱한 사람들을
죽였다구요
You guys bug out of Pakistan
with a wounded man,
당신네들이 부상자를 데리고
파키스탄에서 빠져나온 지
and a few hours later,
the US is nuking the joint?
몇 시간만에 미국이 거기에
핵공격을 퍼부었는데
How do you connect the dots?
당신이라면 어떻게
추론하겠어요?
기회가 있을 때
SEAL 팀을 죽였어야지
You should've killed
those SEALs
when you had the chance.
This is my island.
여긴 내 섬이야
If I allow your presence,
자네들을 묵인해주려면
뭔가 오가는 게 있어야지
it comes with certain terms
and conditions.
I could kill you right now.
지금 바로 죽일 수도 있어
Do you want a war?
전쟁을 바라는 건가?
My son is dead.
내 아들은 죽었소
There will be
no burial for your son
자네가 항복할 때까지
그 아이 장례식은 없을 거야
until you surrender.
You're Sam's friend.
- 샘 친구분이시죠
- 네, 대학 동창입니다
Yes. From college.
Mrs. Kendal...
켄달 부인, 남편이 한 일에 대해
어떻게 생각하십니까?
What do you think
about your husband's actions?
He's a government agent
sent to spy on me
정부 요원이에요
절 감시하고 샘을 배신하게
하려고 온 거죠
and turn me against Sam.
You ever give a damn
about getting home?
집으로 돌아갈 생각을
해보긴 한 겁니까?
Sam, if you had objections--
- 샘, 자네가 반대한다면... / - 함장님은
갈 곳이 없는지 몰라도 전 아닙니다!
Maybe you have nowhere to go,
but I do.
영자막 n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
Sync and corrections by n17t01
translated & synced by ruvyn
Last Resort S01E06 "Another Fine Navy Day"
ABC, 2012. 11. 8. 방영
화학 공격 3시간 후
You're never coming back,
안 돌아올 거지?
are you?
I always find my way back,
don't I?
내가 안 돌아온 적 있었어?
What are you doing?
뭐하는 거예요?
I'm gonna be home soon.
곧 돌아올 거야
I promise.
약속해
Pitts.
피츠
Pitts, wake up.
피츠, 일어나!
♪ I'd rather be all alone ♪
♪ now I'm standing on my own ♪
♪ and no longer sad ♪
- What the hell is going on?
- Whoa! Hey, hey, take it easy.
- 대체 무슨 일이지?
- 이봐, 진정해
You take it easy.
진정하라고?
저기 수십 명이 기절해 있다고
There's a hundred people
passed out back there.
Listen, my friend.
You're bleeding, okay?
이봐, 친구...
피가 나잖아, 응?
닦아줄게
Let me help you. I brought--
저 사람들한테 무슨 일이
일어난 건지 말하지 않으면...
You didn't tell me
what happened
to all those people back there.
You don't remember?
기억 못 하는군
Look, it's okay.
이봐, 괜찮아
You're not well.
자넨 아픈 거야
You, those people back there,
you've all been drugged.
자네랑, 저기 사람들 모두
약에 당한 거라구
You need to lie down.
Wait for it to pass.
좀 누워 있어야 돼
약발이 떨어지길
기다리라구
There's blood on your shoes.
- 신발에 피가 묻었는데
- 뭐?
- What? Look--
- Why is there blood on your shoes?
- 어떻게 피가 묻은 거지?
- 뭐? 이봐, 아냐
No. I'm just helping--
- 난 그냥 돕고 있는 거야
- 무슨 일이 일어난 건지 말해!
Tell me what the hell
is going on!
제발 해치진 말게
Don't hurt me, please.
I swear on my mother,
어머니께 걸고 맹세하지
your friends were already dead
when I got here.
내가 왔을 때 저 친구들은
벌써 죽어 있었다구
Aah!
좀 쉬라구, 꼬마야
Rest easy, ma puce.
It will end soon enough.
금새 끝날 테니까
고마워 할 지도 몰라
You might even be grateful.
One more for luck.
혹시 모르니 한 방 더
Aah!
4시간 전
_
화학 공격 20분 전
Thought you were dead.
죽은 줄 알았어
I haven't slept like that
in years.
이렇게 푹 잔 건
몇 년만이야
잠꼬댈 하던데
You talk in your sleep.
뭐라고 했어?
What do I say?
That's between you and whoever
comes in your dream.
너랑... 네 꿈에 나온
누군가의 얘기인 걸
Wouldn't be polite to listen.
엿듣는 건 예의가 아니잖아
Petty Officer
First Class Barry Hopper,
배리 하퍼 하사
마커스 채플린 함장님이시네
Captain Marcus Chaplin.
It's good to see you're
getting your strength back.
기운을 차렸다니 다행일세
We appreciate you guys coming,
but he actually needs his rest.
와주셔서 감사합니다만
아직 더 쉬어야 합니다
1분이면 되네
Only gonna take a minute.
자네도 지금쯤 알고 있겠지만
자네들을 태운 뒤로 세상이 좀 변했네
As I'm sure you're now aware,
the world's a bit different
since we pulled you
out of the water.
네, 팀원들이 알려주더군요
Yeah, the guys
have been filling me in.
자기들도 모르는 건
알려주기 힘들 텐데
Well, they can't tell you
what they don't know.
In recent negotiations,
최근 협상 자리에서 국방장관이
자네들에게 깊은 관심을 보이더군
the Secretary of Defense took
a keen interest in all of you.
He seemed quite determined
to have you and your team
자네와 다른 팀원들을 다시
자기 휘하로 두고 싶어 하던 걸
- back under his control again.
- It seem odd
그런 고위직이 자네한테 그런
관심을 보이다니 좀 이상하지?
that someone that high up
is so concerned with you?
말씀드렸듯이
와주셔서 감사합니다만...
Like I said, we appreciate
you stopping by and all--
No, no, no, they got a point.
Let 'em get to it.
아냐 아냐, 요점이 있을 텐데
들어보기나 하자구
You do have a point, don't you?
요점이 있으시겠죠?
Here it is--
있지
If your mission in Pakistan--
자네들이 파키스탄에서
했던 임무 말인데
something you know about it
or something you did--
그곳에서 알게 된 거라든가
그곳에서 한 일이라든가...
makes it unsafe
for you to go back home,
그것 때문에 돌아가기
위험해진 거라면...
you're welcome here.
머물러도 좋네
장난합니까?
당신이 뭔데?
Are you kidding me?
Who do you think you are?
You nuked your own country,
you piece of--
조국에 핵을 쏜 주제에!
이런 개 같은...
You're dead already,
넌 죽은 목숨이야!
이 오만한 새끼야
you arrogant son of a bitch.
You're just too stupid
to fall down.
머릴 숙이는 법도
모르는 멍청한 새끼!
둥그런 빵처럼 생긴 건데
물사과라고...
The ones that look like
round doughnuts, the wax apples.
다 떨어졌어
이게 다야
No more, no more.
This is it.
You want more?
Let in some boats.
다른 걸 원하면
배를 오게 하던지
- 킹과 하퍼가...
- 이봐!
- So King and Hopper--
- Hey.
You owe me more.
모자라
After you leave, they have
a little bedside chat.
함장님께서 나가시자
둘이 속닥이더니
Then king puts the other two
gorillas on the door.
그 고릴라들한테 문을 지키게
하고는 킹이 사라졌습니다
He bugs out.
I don't even know how
to eat these things.
- 이건 어떻게 먹는지도
모르는데 / - 장교님들
- Sirs.
- COB.
- 갑판장
- 승조원들은 어때요?
How's the crew, COB?
할리 오토바이처럼 시끄럽죠
Firing like a one-kick harley.
Just swapping out the crew now.
지금 근무교대하는 중입니다
Sir, you gonna eat
those hairy balls?
- 그 털공을 드실 겁니까?
- 뭔지도 모르는 걸
I don't even know
what they are.
촘촘이라고 하죠
여주 같은 겁니다
Chom chom.
It's like litchi.
열대과일 전문가인 줄은
몰랐는데요, 갑판장
Hadn't pegged you for
an exotic fruit man, COB.
Don't ask, don't tell.
'묻지도 말하지도 말라'
So the SEALs are
starting to close ranks?
그럼 SEAL이 똘똘
뭉치고 있다는 건가?
네, 뭔가를 숨기고
있는 게 분명합니다
Yeah, they're definitely
hiding something.
I don't see a shoving match
getting us anywhere, though.
하지만 이런 밀치기 시합으론
아무것도 얻지 못할 겁니다
Secretary Curry
nearly popped an eyeball
내가 그 애들을 입에 올리자
커리 장관 눈이 등잔만 해졌지
last time I mentioned
those boys.
Let's see what happens
걔들이 기자를 만나고 싶다고
한다면 어떻게 나오나 볼까
when I tell him
they want to meet the press.
_
콜로라도 함 부장의 아내
변호사와 한밤중의 '상담'
That's Sam's wife.
- 샘 아내잖아요
- 그러게요
I know, but who's that
handsome gentleman she's with?
그런데 함께 있는
이 미남은 누굴까요?
- 지라르 양
- 창 닫아요
- Ms. Girard.
- Get rid of it.
커리 국방장관과
얘기하고 싶은데
I want to talk
to Secretary of Defense Curry.
Can you work your magic?
- 연결해줄 수 있겠소?
- 네, 잠시만요
Yes. A few minutes.
영상통화를 해야 하오
And I'm gonna need
a video feed.
I'd like to see his reaction
to what I have to say.
내 말에 어떻게
반응하는지 보고 싶거든
We have cameras.
카메라는 있죠
We do have, uh, cameras.
네, 카메라는... 있죠
Hey, Sam.
저기, 샘
Have a look.
저거 봐요
이게 뭐죠?
What the hell is that?
That's the guy
keeping your wife warm.
어떤 남자가 당신 아낼
따뜻하게 해주고 있네요
I'm sorry.
You think that's funny?
- 미안한데 이게 재밌나요?
- 슬픈 거죠, 정말로
I think it's sad, actually.
그런 식으로 말할 거면
일어나서 해보시지
Well, you stand up if you're
gonna talk to me like that, man.
그만, 부장
집중하라구
Easy, XO stay on target.
Hey, you, get rid of that
and get me my video feed. Now.
당신은 저거 내리고
영상통화 연결해주시오
빨리!
Hey.
저기...
I'm sorry. I don't know
what's wrong with him today.
미안해요
오늘 왜 저러는지
모르겠네요
No, it's fine. It's fine.
It's just a picture.
아뇨, 괜찮아요
그냥 사진 한 장인데요
I thought you'd be pleased.
더 기뻐할 줄 알았는데
You said you couldn't go home
because Hopper was hurt,
하퍼가 아파서
못 간다고 했잖아
but now he's okay, so--
근데...
- 이제 괜찮아졌으니...
- 갈 수 있겠다고?
So now I can go.
맞아
Yeah.
I'm ecstatic.
춤이라도 추고 싶네
So...
그럼...
are you...
그럴 거야?
going home?
- 돌아갈 거야?
- 아직 결정 못 했어
I haven't decided.
가고 싶으면서
But you want to.
내가 뭘 원하느냐는
중요하지 않아
Doesn't matter what I want.
I got a job to do,
내겐 해야 할 일이 있는데 금문교가
여기까지 연결된 것도 아니니까
and the bay bridge
doesn't reach this far.
항상 보고 싶었는데...
I've always wanted
to see the...
세상에
Oh, my God.
That looks like my mom.
우리 엄마잖아!
What?
뭐?
Hey. Hey.
- Aah!
- Hold on!
꽉 잡아!
Ah!
왜 이렇게 머리가 아프지?
Why does my head hurt so much?
You getting through?
- 연결됐나요? / - 중계기에 문제가
있지만 금방 될 거예요
Trouble with the relay,
but soon, I think.
You need anything?
뭐 좀 드시겠습니까?
No, I'm okay.
아냐, 괜찮아
And what about my video feed?
영상통화는?
I'm working on it.
- 작업 중이에요
- 빨리 좀 해요
Well, the sooner the better.
이봐요
Look, mate, unless you know
how to do my job,
당신이 할 줄 모르는 일이면
그냥 가만히 있어요
why don't you just chill out
and let me do my job?
일 좀 할 수 있게!
Okay.
알았어요
We got a serious issue in town.
마을에 심각한
문제가 생겼습니다
- 잠시만요, 갑판장
- 네, 회선 연결됐어요
One second, COB.
- Okay, your line is open.
- Yeah, hold the line.
계속 열어놓으시오
나이젤, 영상이 필요한데
Nigel, I need the video feed.
다리나 꼬고
앉아 있지, 언니
Cross your legs, sister.
I said I was working on it.
작업 중이라고 했잖아
I don't know
what your problem is,
대체 뭐가 문젠지
모르겠지만
but you sort it out,
and you sort it out right now.
빨리 해결하는 게
신상에 이로울 거야
Problem sorted.
해결됐네
Please, everyone, just--
just stop talking.
제발 모두들
그냥... 닥쳐요
Please.
부탁이야
너무 시끄럽다구
Oh, it's so loud in here.
Same thing's happening
all over town.
마을에도 똑같은 일이
벌어지고 있습니다
I've seen this party before,
and it's not good.
전에도 이런 걸 본 적 있습니다
상황이 안 좋아요
약에 당한 겁니다
We've been dosed.
It's a pretty serious drug
called BZ.
BZ라는 심각한 약물입니다
Military designed it,
nickname Buzz.
군에서 개발했죠
'버즈'라고 불립니다
I was a Guinea pig.
훌륭한 음악이 나오던 시절
저와 동료들이 실험에 자원했었죠
Me and some buddies volunteered
back when music didn't suck.
Extra cash was nice,
돈을 두둑히 줬거든요
but even at a low dose,
it was no picnic.
소량을 투여받았는데도
장난이 아니었습니다
- 좋은 소식은 없나요?
- 죽진 않습니다
There any good news?
Well, it doesn't kill you.
찾았습니다
Found it.
"BZ는 군용 무력화 제제로
향이 없는 물질이다"
Um, "BZ is an odorless
military incapacitating agent.
The central effects include
delusions, poor judgment,
"주요 효과는 망상, 판단력 저하, 기억상실,
편집증, 지각상실... 환각이다"
memory blackouts, paranoia,
illusions, hallucinations.
Ultimately, the victims
will lose consciousness."
"대상은 결국 의식을 잃게 된다"
Symptoms last
about eight hours.
증세는 8시간 동안
지속된답니다
This is a coordinated attack.
- 이건 양동작전이야
- 하지만 어떻게 한 겁니까?
Yeah, but how'd it get here?
제가 받은 실험에선
레모네이드에 탔었죠
Well, in the experiment,
they mixed it with lemonade.
이 섬의 수원은 하나뿐이지
Well, the island's only got
one main water supply.
그렇다면 모두 정신을
잃게 될 겁니다
- They dose that, they knock out everyone.
- Smart.
- 멋진 작전이군요
- 해독제는?
Countermeasures?
절 깨어나게 하려고
아드레날린을 주사했죠
Well, the docs used adrenaline
to snap me out of it.
에피네프린 제제, 에피펜,
알레르기 주사도 가능합니다
Can also use epinephrine,
epipens, allergy shots.
Colorado has those
in the med locker.
콜로라도 함 의료함에 있습니다
이곳 병원에도 있을 겁니다
Hospital here
would have some, too.
We gotta move fast.
빨리 움직여야 합니다
All right, COB,
Lieutenant, you're with me.
갑판장과 대위는 나와 함께
함을 잠수시켜 숨기도록 하지
We're gonna dive
and hide the sub.
Ride it out with the meds
we have on board.
함에 있는 약품으로 견뎌보세
부장, 자넨 섬을 맡아주게
XO, you've got the island.
Get the epipens
from the hospital,
병원에서 에피펜을
구해서 자네와
inject yourself
and enough crewmen
EWS(조기경보소)를 수리하고 방어할 수
있을 만큼의 인원에게 주사하도록
to repair and defend the EWS.
Stay awake and alive
for the next eight hours,
앞으로 8시간 동안
살아남도록 깨어 있게
'cause something bad's coming.
나쁜 일이 일어날 테니
Just entering deep water, sir.
잠수 심도 진입했습니다
항로 1-5-3
Heading 1-5-3.
Ahead two-thirds.
Steady as she goes.
조타 2/3
항로 유지하도록
괜찮은가, 대위?
Are you still with me,
Lieutenant?
All the way, sir.
- 괜찮습니다
- 갑판장, 상황보고
Report, COB.
의료품 목록을 보면 코르테즈가
에피펜 20개를 가져올 겁니다
According to
this drug inventory,
Cortez should be coming back
with 20 epipens.
Only 20?
- 20개뿐이라구요? / - 잠수함엔
언제나 물자가 부족한 법입니다
There's not a lot of bees
on submarines, ma'am.
Essential personnel on the conn
and engine room get shots first.
지통실 필수 인원과
기관실에 먼저 배급하게
Department heads after that.
- 그 다음엔 각 실장들에게
- 발작하는 승조원들이 많을 겁니다
That's gonna leave
a whole lot of the crew
crawling out of their skins.
So we babysit
and hope for the best.
그럼 잘 달래면서
최선을 바랄 수밖에
Why should today
be any different?
뭐 다른 날과
다를 것도 없군요
Sir, they're gone.
함장님
없어졌습니다
Sir, the epi shots--
medical locker was broken into.
에피펜들이... 의료함이
부서져 있었습니다
- What are you talking about?
- Someone stole 'em.
- 무슨 소리야?
- 누가 훔쳐갔습니다
So we have nothing?
그럼 아무것도 없다고?
And some of the crew's
already freaking out,
승조원 일부도 벌써
발작하고 있습니다
acting weird.
What do we do, sir?
어떻게 합니까
함장님?
We dive.
잠수한다
You owe me!
You owe me more!
모자라!
모자라다구!
Hey, get off of me!
이거 놔!
Aah!
Christine, what are you doing?
크리스틴
뭐하는 거야?
You're never coming home,
are you?
안 돌아올 거지?
What?
뭐?
죄송합니다
I'm sorry, sir.
Just really thirsty.
목이 마를 뿐입니다
Pitts, it's okay.
Come with me. We gotta--
- 피츠, 괜찮아. 같이 가세
- 물이 필요합니다
I need water.
- 물을 마셔야 합니다
- 피츠, 피츠, 내 말 듣게
Hey, Pitts. Pitts, Pitts,
Pitts, listen to me.
We're under attack, okay?
공격을 받은 거야
약에 당한 거라구
We have been drugged.
I need your help. Come on.
- 자네 도움이 필요하네
- 네, 부장님
Yes, sir.
하지만 먼저 물을
마셔야 합니다
But I gotta get water!
It's in the water, Pitts!
물에 약이 들었어, 피츠!
_
화학 공격 3시간 후
You may find also
또 현기증이 일 거나
졸릴 수도 있다
yourself feeling lightheaded
or sleepy.
That's fine.
괜찮다
When that happens,
그런 일이 생기면
임무에서 벗어나
I want you to step away
from your position
and secure yourself
in your bunk.
자기 침상으로 가서 눕도록
I realize we're running...
나도 지금 기간...
I realize we're running
a skeleton crew.
기간승조원뿐이란 걸 안다
But we will ride out this storm
그래도 우리는
견뎌낼 것이다
hovering here at s--
a safe depth
이곳 안- 안전한
심도에서 머물다가
and return to port unharmed.
무사히 귀황할 것이다
이상
Captain out.
Hey, man.
어이
- 어이
- 지금 이상해?
You messed up?
You don't seem too messed up.
- 이상해 보이진 않는데
- 자네도
Neither do you.
각성제를 좀 먹었지
그 이쑤시개로 뭐하려고?
Popped some "go pills." Where
you goin' with the toothpick?
Got some business with Serrat.
세라트한테 볼 일이 있어
Guess that makess u partners.
그럼 같은 팀이군
아직 정신을 못 차렸어
Ah, she's still out of it.
That BZ hit her hard.
- BZ를 많이 먹었나봐
- 채식주의자인가 보지
Probably a vegetarian.
날 좋아하는 것 같은데
I think she likes me, though.
Come on! Wake up, already!
이봐!
빨리 일어나!
Here.
Give her these.
여기
- 이걸 놔줘
- 두 대나?
- Two?
- Whatever it takes to bring her back.
- 깨우려면 어쩔 수 없지
- 너무 많아! 죽을 수도 있어!
It's too much.
You're going to stop her heart.
혈관을 찾아봐
15분 안에 통신해야 돼
Try to hit a vein or something.
I want that comm up in 15.
여자가 죽으면
아무것도 못 한다고!
You're not going to get
anything fixed if you kill her.
She's French.
She's all heart.
프랑스 년이잖아
심장도 클 거야
괜찮을 거라구
She'll be fine.
They got cross-fire.
십자 포화 대형이야
세 걸음도 못 가겠는 걸
We won't get three steps.
Let's go, sweetheart.
Up and at 'em.
자, 이쁜이
일어나봐
Are you mad?
미쳤어? 무슨 짓이야?
그럴 필요는...
What is wrong with you?
There's no need for you to--
아, 닥쳐!
Oh, my God. Shut up.
Look, I don't have time
to do it the nice way.
이봐, 예의를 차릴
시간이 없다구
우리 약속은 아주 단순했지
이런 건 약속에 없었잖아!
We made
a very simple arrangement.
This was not a part of it.
널 죽이지 않겠다고도 했지만
지금은 뭐라도 가능하지
Neither was killing you,
but everything's negotiable.
I gotta tell you,
이 말은 해야겠군
I'm really kind of pissed
you broke my arm.
내 팔을 부러뜨려줘서
정말 화났다구
They got Hopper.
- 하퍼가 잡혔군
- 우유라도 마시지 그래
You should drink more milk.
Did you enjoy your
cavity search, by the way?
그런데 항문 검사는
마음에 들던가?
Did you?
넌?
이제 어디에
없는진 알았으니
Now that we know
where it is not,
let's talk about where it is.
어디에 있는지 말해볼까
말했듯이
어디 있는지 모른다
Told you,
I don't know where it is.
That attitude is gonna get
a lot of people killed
그런 태도 때문에
많은 사람이 죽을 거야
for no reason.
아무 이유도 없이
Who are these guys?
이 녀석들은 누구지?
What the hell
are they looking for?
대체 뭘 찾고 있는 거야?
화학 공격 1시간 후
_
공격을 받은 거야
약에 당한 거라구
We're under attack, okay?
We have been drugged.
I need your help. Come on.
화학 공격 1시간 후
- 자네 도움이 필요하네
- 네, 부장님
Yes, sir.
But I gotta get water!
하지만 먼저 물을
마셔야 합니다
It's in the water, Pitts!
물에 약이 들었어, 피츠!
You're never
coming back, are you?
안 돌아올 거지?
당신은 환각이야
환각이란 걸 알아
Oh, God. You're not real.
I know you're not real.
날 못 믿어?
Don't you trust me?
Don't you trust yourself?
스스로를 못 믿어?
Aah!
Ah.
Who are you?
누구지?
What are you talking about?
- 무슨 말씀이십니까?
- 넌 누구냐고?
Who are you?
Whoa. XO, hang on.
You know me.
잠깐, 부장님
아시잖습니까
I don't know you.
What are you doing in here?
난 널 몰라
여기서 뭐하는 거지?
My arm was broken.
I had to-- I had to set it.
팔이 부러져서
고정시키고 있습니다
Did you kill those men
out there?
- 자네가 저 사람들을 죽인 건가?
- 아니, 아닙니다
No, no, no, no, no,
it was-- it was Hopper, sir.
하퍼였습니다
He went-- he went...
He went crazy,
갑자기 미쳐 날뛰더니
저흴 공격했습니다
attacked us.
He broke my arm.
제 팔을 부러뜨린 것도
그 녀석입니다
No. I don't know you.
I don't know you.
아냐
난 널 몰라
모른다구
It's that drug, sir.
It's messing with your mind.
약 때문입니다
약 때문에 그런 겁니다
I'm Jim McClure.
I'm in supply.
- 짐 맥클루어, 보급실입니다
- 아냐, 아냐
No, no, no, no.
기다리십시오
절 아시잖습니까
Hang on. You know me.
You're Lieutenant Commander
Sam Kendal.
샘 켄달 소령님, 콜로라도 함
부장님 아니십니까
You're the XO on the Colorado.
It's just the drugs, sir.
It's--
약 때문입니다
그래서 혼란스러우신 겁니다
It gets you confused.
그 약 때문에 모든 사람이
미친 거 아닙니까
That drug is making
everyone crazy.
It makes you see things,
think things that aren't--
환각을 보기도 하고
차-착각을 하게 만들기도 하고
aren't real.
You okay?
괜찮으십니까?
I...
- 난...
- 도움이 필요하십니까?
You need help?
I can help you.
도와드리겠습니다
I, uh, I need epi shots.
에피 주사가 필요하네
Epinephrine, it-- it helps
counteract the...
에피네프린 말이야
해독제 역할을...
Already checked.
벌써 확인해봤습니다만...
They're-- they're gone.
- He's unconscious.
- Yeah.
의식을 잃었습니다
Did you want me to try
and get him to a bunk or--
침상으로 옮기는 게 어떻...
We'll move him
when the COB gets back.
갑판장이 돌아오면
옮기도록 하지
Sir, I'm feeling a lit--
I--
함장님...
제 상태가...
전...
I need you here, Lieutenant,
with me.
자네가 필요하네, 대위
정신 차리게
With me.
그럴 수 있겠나!
Can you handle that?
Yes, sir.
네, 함장님
I'm here, sir.
정신 차렸습니다
- 1번 기계실에 화재가 났군
- 화재가 공기저장 탱크까지 번지면...
We got a fire in machinery one.
If that fire gets to the air
in the storage tanks--
알고 있네
I'm aware. Shut down
the oxygen header, Lieutenant.
산소 공급을 끊게, 대위
How much air
does that leave us?
- 그럼 저희가 숨쉴 공기가-
- 마지막까지 견뎌봐야지
Whatever you can smell.
Machinery one, conn.
Report.
1번 기계실, 지통실이다
화재 상황보고하라
Report status on the fire.
They could all be passed out
down there.
모두 정신을 잃었을 겁니다
COB!
갑판장!!
COB, where are you?
갑판장, 어디 있나?
Lieutenant Shepard,
you have the conn.
셰퍼드 대위
자네가 조함하게
Sir.
함장님
If someone doesn't get that fire
out and the air back on,
누군가 화재를 진압하고
다시 산소를 공급하지 않으면
we all go to sleep,
never wake up.
모두 잠든 채 두번 다시
깨어나지 못할 거야
Keep her steady.
평형을 유지하게
I need to get ahold
of the Colorado
콜로라도 함에 연락해서
도와줄 건 없는지 확인해야 해
to see if they need any help.
Oh, there's power.
전원은 들어옵니다
Can you key the signal
for me, XO?
암호키를 입력해
주시겠습니까, 부장님?
Mm-hmm.
어째서 애를
가지지 않았지, 샘?
How come
we don't have kids, Sam?
Is it 'cause you're never home?
당신이 항상 집에 없어서?
Look...
저기...
We gotta wake up
your French friend.
그 프랑스 여잘 깨워야 합니다
You hear me?
들으셨습니까?
Hey. We gotta get that French
se?orita back on her feet.
부장님!
그 프랑스 아가씰
깨워야 합니다
Only way this thing's
getting fixed.
그래야 여길
고칠 수 있습니다
Hey. Sophie, wake up.
소피, 일어나요
_
Hey, look at me.
이봐요
Look, look--
hey, open your eyes.
눈을 떠요
날 봐봐요
You need to focus on me.
Here, look.
_
소피, 일어나야 합니다
무선통신을 복구해야 해요
Sophie, you gotta wake up.
I need to get
the radio fixed now.
He will kill us...
all for money.
그 사람이
우릴 죽일 거야...
다 돈 때문이야...
부장님...
XO...
need you
to key the signal again.
암호키를 다시 입력해
주셔야겠습니다
이러고 싶진 않았지만...
I was hoping
to avoid this, but...
지금이나 나중이나
언제든 죽일 수 있으니까
I guess I can always
kill you later.
Hi, daddy.
안녕, 아빠
Jeffrey?
제프리?
You came home!
돌아왔구나!
당신이 돌아와서
너무 행복해, 여보
I am so happy
you're here, babe.
Aren't you gonna sit down?
안 앉을 거야?
You were gone for so long,
너무 오래 떠나 있어서
안 돌아오는 줄 알았어
I thought you were never
coming home.
Why are you always
leaving me alone, Sam?
어째서 항상 날 혼자
놔두는 거야, 샘?
I don't want to leave you alone.
But I have to. I'm sorry.
그러고 싶진 않지만
해야 하니까. 미안해
안 미안하면서
You're not sorry.
When Marcus offered
you that desk job,
마커스가 사무직 얘길 했을 때
당신 처음 한 생각이...
your first thought was...
God, I hope Christine
doesn't find out about that.
'크리스틴이 알면
안 되는데'였으면서
No, it wasn't.
아니야
Hmm? It wasn't?
아니라고?
Look, I just want
my own command. That's all.
언젠가 나도 함장이
되고 싶었던 것뿐이야
그것도 크리스틴이 몰랐으면
했던 것 중에 하나였어?
Is that just another
one of those things
that you hope Christine
doesn't find out about?
You don't know what it's like.
당신은 어떤지 몰라
고문당하는 거 말야?
To be tortured?
What did they do to you?
어떤 일을 당한 거야?
I love you.
사랑해
Don't you want me to love you?
- 당신을 사랑하길 바라지 않는 거야?
- 당연히 바라지
Of course I do.
- 그럼 왜 날 못 믿어?
- 난 당신을 믿어
Then why don't you trust me?
I do trust you.
그럼 어땠는데?
What is it then?
I don't trust myself.
날 못 믿는 거야
Well, you shouldn't.
그럴 만도 하지
And you shouldn't trust him.
저 사람도 믿지 말았어야지
Help me out, would you?
도와주시겠습니까?
팔이 하나뿐이라 말입니다
I only got one arm.
Damn, that hurts.
많이 아픕니다
Um...
Are you okay?
괜찮아요?
_
잠시만 기다리시면
금방 깨어날 겁니다
She'll come around.
Just give her a minute.
Hey, remind me of your name.
이름이 뭐라고 했지?
McClure.
맥클루어입니다
- McClure in supply.
- Yeah.
- 보급실 맥클루어?
- 네
And you report to
senior watch...
그럼 자네 실장이...
Chief Arnold.
Bill Arnold from Ohio.
아놀드 실장입니다
오하이오 출신 빌 아놀드
Right. Right, Bill Arnold.
맞아, 빌 아놀드
Right, right, right. Sorry.
그래, 맞아
미안하네
He got promoted last month.
지난 달에 진급했는데
Ohh!
Oh!
Who are you?
넌 누구야?!
Huh?! Why are you here?
여긴 왜 온 거지?!
What are you doing, Sam?
- 뭐하는 거예요?
- 다 바로잡을 거야
I'm gonna fix everything.
You'll see, Christine.
두고 보라구
크리스틴
I'm gonna be home soon.
I promise.
금방 돌아갈 거야
약속할게
약속해
I promise.
Who are you?
넌 누구냐?
Tell me.
말해
Tell me!
말해!
_
화학 공격 4시간 후
모르겠는데
I don't know.
Guess.
찍어봐
"U"?
U?
Hmm.
You're terrible at this.
정말 못하네
By the way,
it was "gypsy."
참고로 정답은
'gypsy'였어
How are we doing back there?
- 다 돼가나?
- 1초만요
One second.
Yeah, you keep saying that.
계속 그 소린데
You do know how long
one second is, right?
1초가 어느 정도의
시간인진 알고 있지?
It takes how long it takes.
재촉한다고 더 빨리
되는 게 아니랍니다
Mm.
Hey, hey!
Like a Christmas tree.
크리스마스 트리 같구만
Joyeux Noel, huh, mon ami?
메리 크리스마스군
응? 친구
You are not my friend.
- 당신은 내 친구가 아니에요
- 가슴이 찢어지는군
Devastating. So do we have
a working comm or what?
그래 이제 무선통신이
되는 건가 아닌가?
I have to, um, reset power
for the antenna downstairs.
전원을... 껐다 켜야 돼요
안테나 때문인데
아래층에 있어요
Go with her.
같이 가
Almost out of your hair,
Mr. Serrat.
폐 끼치는 것도 거의
끝나가는군, 세라트 씨
I'll miss you.
그리울 거야
근데 나중에 싸우기 귀찮으니까
지금 얘길 해주는 건데...
Yeah, well,
I'm gonna bring this up now
'cause I don't want you
pitching a fit later.
When she's done, she's dead.
저 여자 일이 끝나면
죽일 거야
What?
뭐?
No, no, this isn't-- no!
아냐, 그건...
안 돼!
Good, get it out now
그래, 지금 다 쏟아내라구
저 여잔 우리 얼굴을 봤어
'cause, yeah, she's seen
a lot of faces.
그럼 내가 책임을 지지
내가 확실하게...
I will be responsible for her.
I will make sure--
What was that?
뭐라고?
There's no reason to--
죽일 필요는...!
It's a long game.
이건 오래 갈 거래야
Don't get yourself hanged
on the first day.
첫날부터 목매달리고 싶은 건가
Get Hopper ready to move.
하퍼 녀석
이송 준비해
And tie him up good this time
이번엔 잘 묶으라구
so he doesn't screw
anyone's health plan.
아무도 의료보험료
오르지 않게 말야
That's it?
- 그게 다야?
- 하나 더 있어요
One more.
Easy. Easy.
Easy. You okay?
진정하세요
괜찮아요?
I'm gonna get you out of here,
but we need your help.
당신을 구해줄 테지만
당신이 도와줘야 해요
아무일도 없는 것처럼
위층으로 올라갈 겁니다
We're gonna go back upstairs
like there's nothing wrong.
I'm gonna be right behind you.
- 내가 뒤를 따를 거에요
- 그 뒤엔 내가 있구요
And I'll be right behind him.
방에 들어가면 빨리 움직여요
통신기로 가서 몸을 숙여요
When you go in, you go in fast.
You get to the comm,
get down on the floor.
You understand?
- 알았어요?
- 네, 알겠어요
Yes, I understand.
Okay.
- 좋아요
- 이봐
Hey.
I got the cross-fire twins.
십자 대형은 내가 맡을 테니
당신은 다른 녀석을 맡아
You take the other one.
Okay, remember,
broken arm stays alive.
알겠네, 하지만 팔이 부러진
녀석은 살려둬야 해
I don't know what you think
you're fighting for, friend.
자네가 뭘 위해 싸운다고
생각하는지 모르겠군, 친구
Flag waving, saluting,
world policing--
바람에 날리는 국기,
경례, 세계의 경찰 노릇...
It's all just part of
the commercial.
전부 그냥 광고일 뿐이잖나
Well?
- 그래서?
- 거의, 거의 다
Almost. Almost.
I-I am very close.
거의 다 됐어요
이제...
A few final connections.
마지막으로
연결만 하면...
좋아
Good.
암호키 입력해줄래요?
Will you key the signal for me?
Say when.
말만 하셔
Almost.
거의 다 됐어요
Aah!
Who are these people?
Who sent them?
- 이 사람들은 뭐야, 누가
보낸 거야? / - 나도 몰라!
I don't know.
What are you doing?
He just saved your life.
무슨 짓이에요?
당신 목숨을 구했잖아요
What do they want?!
- 뭘 원했던 거지?!
- 저 사람!
Him and his friend Hopper.
하퍼라는 친구하고
There was to be no harm.
아무도 안 다칠 거랬어
They told me, put their drug
in the water,
자기들 약을 물에 넣으면
당신들이 모두 잠들 거라더군
and you would go to sleep.
당신들이 깨어날 때면 이 섬에
있을 이유가 사라질 거라고
When you woke, there would be
no reason for you to stay.
They promised me
my island back!
내 섬을 돌려주겠다고
약속했다구!
They lied.
거짓말이었지
That is what I know.
The rest is as you see.
내가 아는 건 그게 다야
나머진 당신도 알겠지
Get out of here.
꺼져
- Please help me get the comm back online.
- Hopper.
무선통신을 연결하게 도와줘요
Hopefully there's still
a sub out there somewhere.
운이 좋으면 잠수함도
아직 무사하겠죠
Air.
공기...
You gotta turn
the oxygen back on.
산소를 다시
틀어야 합니다
You sleepy?
졸리니?
Yeah?
그래?
산소 부족
Me too.
나도 그렇단다
- 오늘은 어떤 얘길 들려줄까?
- 공작새 얘기요
What story
you want to do tonight?
The-- the peacock.
That's a good one.
좋은 얘기지
Okay.
그러자꾸나
A peacock...
공작새가...
spreading his gorgeous tail
아름다운 꼬리를 펼치고는
made fun of a crane
that was passing by.
지나가던 두루미를 놀렸단다
The peacock...
공작새가...
laughed at the dusty color
of the crane's feathers
두루미 깃털이 추레하다고
비웃으며 말하길...
and said...
"I am robed like a king,
"난 왕처럼 차려입었는데"
while you have not
a bit of color on your wings."
"네 날개엔 아무런
색깔도 없구나"
"That's true,"
replied the crane.
"그건 그렇지"
두루미가 대답했어
"But I soar to the heights
of heaven.
"그래도 난 천국까지
높이 날 수 있지"
While you only walk below,
"하지만 넌... 고작..."
"땅 위를... 걸을 뿐..."
"마치..."
like a...
like a rat."
"쥐새끼처럼"
산소 부족, 일산화탄소
이산화탄소 과다
EWS to Colorado.
Come in, Colorado.
EWS에서 콜로라도에
응답하라, 콜로라도
Are you sure it's working?
연결된 겁니까?
Yes, it should be.
네,그럴 거에요
Come in, Colorado.
This is the XO.
콜로라도 응답하라
부장이다
Can you please, can you
just recheck the signal?
부탁인데 감도를
다시 확인해줄래요?
The signal is good.
I have checked.
감도는 좋아요
확인했어요
Um, perhaps they have
a problem--
- 아마 뭔가 문제가...
- 다시 감도 확인해줄래요? 제발!
Can you please just
recheck the signal? Please.
Don't get angry, okay?
I'm doing my best.
화내지 말아요
나도 최선을 다 하고 있다구요
I'm not. I'm not.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
그런 게 아니에요
미안합니다
I'm sorry. I'm not.
I'm not.
- 화낸 게 아니에요
- 안 그래도 힘들어요
It is difficult in this place
여기 있는 모든 사람이요
for everyone.
You seem to be handling it
very well.
- 잘 견디고 있잖아요
- 장담하지만 아니에요
I promise you, I'm not.
There is a line of morals,
okay?
윤리에도 선이란 게
있는 거에요
알았어요?
When you cross this line,
you never have peace.
그 선을 넘으면 다시는
평온을 찾을 수 없어요
Mm.
You-- you have
some blood on your forehead.
이-이마에 피가 묻었어요
Sorry.
미안해요
Uh, EWS to Colorado.
Come in, Colorado.
EWS에서 콜로라도에
응답하라, 콜로라도
EWS to Colorado.
Come in, Colorado.
EWS에서 콜로라도에
응답하라, 콜로라도
Roger, EWS.
알았다, EWS
We're about 5 miles out,
섬에서 5마일 거리이며
잠수함은 무사하다
and it looks like
the sub's all right.
We'll wait for the crew
to wake up, and we'll
승조원들이 깨어난 후
make our way back
once we get an all clear.
잠수함 점검이 끝나면
귀항하겠다
How are things on the beach?
귀국은 어떤가?
EWS is secure, sir.
EWS는 무사합니다
Not without a body count,
though,
하지만 SEAL 팀 두 명을 포함
사상자가 발생했습니다
including two
of the SEALs--
Vogler and Monk.
보글러와 몽크가
죽었습니다
Roger that. Colorado out.
알았다
콜로라도 통신 끝
Why'd those guys
want me and you?
- 나와 널 노린 이유가 뭐지?
- 뭐라고 생각해?
Why do you think?
파키스탄에서 우리가 그 방에 들어갔잖아
이 전쟁의 이유를 아는 건 우리 둘뿐이야
We were the two
in the room in Pakistan.
We're the only ones who know
why the bullets started flying.
All I know is, we killed the guy
we were sent in to save.
내가 아는 건 우리가 구하러 갔던
사람을 죽였다는 것뿐이야
I still don't know why.
난 아직 이유도 모른다구
The mission directive
got changed
임무 지시가 구출에서
암살로 변경됐어
from extraction to elimination.
I wasn't given new orders.
난 그런 명령 못 받았는데
I was.
내가 받았지
Enter.
들어오게
Sir, relief crew is on board.
교대인원이 승함했습니다
Everyone else
is already ashore.
벌써 모두 해안에 상륙했습니다
함장님이 타실 보트도 준비 끝났습니다
I've got a skiff waiting to
take you back if you're ready.
I'm just gonna scrape off
the fuzz, Lieutenant.
면도부터 하고, 대위
After 30 years of shaving
in the Navy,
해군에서 30년이나 면도했더니
육지에서 베이는 일이 많아서 말야
I have a tendency
to cut myself on land.
알겠습니다. 당분간 제가 면도날을
잡을 일은 없겠지만 말입니다
Understood. Don't think
I'll be holding anything sharp
for a little while.
I'll be right up.
금방 끝날 걸세
내통자는 세라트가
분명합니다
Serrat was obviously
the man on the inside.
I don't know how he got the BZ,
어떻게 BZ를 구했는진 모르겠지만
그 녀석에 물에 탄 겁니다
but he got it in the water.
If their leader
survives the gunshot,
두목이 총격전에서 살아남았다면
물어볼 수 있었을 텐데
maybe we can ask him.
It's interesting that someone
was able to contact him
누군가가 그와 연락이 닿아 공격을
할 수 있었다는 게 흥미롭군
and set up the attack.
Maybe he's got a radio
or-- or a sat phone?
무전기나... 위성전화를
가지고 있지 않나 싶습니다
Or maybe someone
on our crew helped him.
아니면 승조원 가운데
누군가가 도와줬겠지
You think someone on our crew
is working...
승조원 가운데
첩자가 있다고...
Working for who?
누구의 첩자일까?
I don't know.
나도 모르네
But when I was unconscious,
someone took my firing key.
그런데 내가 정신을 잃었을 때
내 발사키를 가져간 사람이 있어
We now have no nuclear
launch capabilities.
즉 이제 핵미사일을
발사할 수 없다는 말일세
발사키를 훔치는 게 목적이었다면
어떻게 저희가 아직 살아 있는 겁니까?
If the plan was
to steal the key,
then how come
we're still alive?
That doesn't make any sense.
말이 안 되지 않습니까?
We are defenseless
without our firing key.
발사키가 없으면 방어수단도
사라지지 않습니까
Maybe they want
to make us sweat.
우릴 겁먹게 만들려는 게지
아마 지금 오고 있을지도
Maybe they're on the way here.
Maybe their plan was to
extract their men first.
먼저 첩자를 빼낼
생각인지도 몰라
Either way,
we have to find the key.
어쨌든 발사키는 찾아야 하네
You should get that
taken care of.
치료부터 받아야겠는 걸
I will.
- 그럴 겁니다
- 거친 싸움이었나보군
Must have been
a hell of a fight.
Honestly, I don't remember.
솔직히 기억이 안 납니다
It'll come back to you.
곧 기억날 걸세
Most of it, at least.
적어도 대부분은
화학 공격 3시간 후
Who are you?
넌 누구냐?
What are you doing here?
여긴 왜 온 거지?
Tell me.
말해
Tell me!
말해!
Stop it.
그만 해요
Stop lying to me, Sam.
거짓말은 이제 그만 해, 샘
- 뭐?
- 안녕, 샘
What?
Hey, Sam. I haven't
seen you for a while.
만난 지 꽤 됐지?
Paul?
폴?
Why are you in my house?
네가 왜 우리 집에 있는 거야?
What are you doing
with my wife?
내 아내랑 뭐하는 거지?
You think Christine's
크리스틴이 영원히 널
기다려줄 여자라고 생각했냐?
the kind of woman
that's gonna wait forever
for you to come home?
I mean, God, look at her.
세상에
좀 보라구
영원히라니, 무슨 말이야?
내가 얘기했잖...
It's not forever. Why is he
saying forever? I told you--
Look how beautiful she is.
얼마나 미인인지 보라구
이런데도 곁을 안 지키냐?
And you're gonna leave this
unattended, buddy?
Women have needs.
여자한테도 욕구가 있다고
네가 못 채워준다면야...
If you don't...
I sure as hell will.
내가 기꺼이 해줄게
이제 끝이 시작되는 거야, 샘
This is the beginning
of the end, Sam.
What are you talking about?
No, it's not.
무슨 말이야?
끝이 아냐
Look.
봐요
당신이 무슨 짓을 했는지
Look what you did to him.
You almost killed him.
거의 죽일 뻔했잖아요
I'll always love you.
영원히 당신을 사랑할 거야
Don't leave me.
- 날 떠나지 마
- 당신을 잃을 순 없어
I can't lose you.
I'm not gonna lose you.
돌아오면 되잖아
Then come home.
I have to finish this.
먼저 이 일을
마무리해야 돼
If I don't, my people will die.
안 그러면 부하들이 죽어
그렇게 놔둘 순 없어
I'm not gonna let that happen.
What about us, Sam?
그럼 우린, 샘?
You do that...
그 주사를 놓으면...
I'll be gone,
난 사라질 거야
and you may never see me again.
그럼 날 다신 볼 수
없을지도 모르는데...
왜 그러려는 거야?
Why would you do that?
Stay.
이렇게 있자
I'm sorry.
미안해
You're never coming back,
are you?
안 돌아올 거지?
Everything's gonna be
different now.
- 이제 모든 게 달라질 거야
- 이러지 마요
Stop it.
I always find my way back,
don't I?
내가 안 돌아온 적 있었어?
What are you doing?
뭐하는 거예요?
I'm gonna be home soon.
금방 돌아갈 거야
I promise.
약속할게
I just, uh, wanted to
say good night
저 그냥, 잘 자라고
인사나 하려구요...
and, uh, to apologize again
for anything I may have--
- 그리고 제가 무슨 짓을 했던지...
- 제정신이 아니었잖아
You weren't yourself, so...
- 그러니까...
- 아뇨, 전...
No, I, um...
I suppose not.
그랬던 것 같네요
Uh, what are you working on?
무슨 작업하는 거예요?
The cameras were still recording
during the attack.
공격받을 동안 카메라가
계속 녹화됐더라구
굉장하네요
저, 잠깐 봐도...?
Oh, brilliant.
Can I-- can I see?
내일 볼래?
Oh, tomorrow?
Um, it's been
a long day, right?
힘든 하루였잖아?
Everything's gonna be
different now. I promise.
이제 모든 게 달라질 거야
이러지 마요
Stop it.
I always find
my way back, don't I?
내가 안 돌아온 적 있었어?
What are you doing?
뭐하는 거예요?
Stop it.
이러지 마요
내가 안 돌아온 적 있었어?
I always find my way back,
don't I?
뭐하는 거예요?
What are you doing?
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
translated & synced by ruvyn